abacus.com 2006-06-16

# Privacy Policy

This is the privacy policy of Abacus site <http://www.abacusglobal.com/>, which shall include, without limitation, the home page, splash page, and all other pages under the same top level domain name, and all content thereon (the "Website") as provided by Abacus ("Abacus" or "we").

Abacus and its employees respect the confidentiality of information given by clients. The personal information concerning clients, collected by Abacus is stored by computers with built-in safeguards to ensure that such information remains private and confidential. 

**Collecting Information**  
This Website requests and collects certain personally identifiable information such as, though not limited to, name, phone number, fax number and e-mail address. All such personal information is processed in accordance with the data protection legislation applicable in the jurisdiction in which Abacus is processing such information. For further information on the collection, storage and your access to information under the legislation in your jurisdiction please contact the Compliance Director at Abacus.

**Cookies**  
"Cookies" are pieces of information that are placed on an individual's computer hard drive to enable the individual to more easily communicate and interact with the Website. We may use cookies to customize your experience on the Website. We may also use cookies to record how many times a user has visited our Website and what pages the user has accessed. You may, however, disallow receiving cookies at any time through your web browser. It is not our intention to use cookies to retrieve information that is unrelated to our Website or your interaction with our Website. 

**IP Address**  
We may collect your IP (Internet Protocol) address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Website. An IP address is a number that is assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. This information does not contain any personally identifiable information about you. Your IP address is also used to help identify you during a particular session and to gather broad demographic data.

**Usage**  
Abacus and its affiliates use information collected on and through this Website to comply with the purpose for which such information was collected and other purposes, as disclosed at the time such information is provided, or as described in this policy. For example, the information collected on and through the Website may be used to send you information about our and our affiliates' products and services and updates to our Website. You also may limit this use by following the instructions in Choice/Opt-out below. We may use the information we gather along with information obtained from other sources, including third parties.

Abacus will only disclose information collected on and through this Website where we have your prior and written approval, where we are compelled to do so by the laws of another jurisdiction, where it is necessary to protect the interests of Abacus, where the information is already in the public domain, where it is deemed to be in the public interest or where it is necessary to promote fraud prevention.

Abacus may transfer, sell or assign information concerning your use of this Website, including without limitation, personally identifiable information that you provide and other information concerning your use of the Website, to third parties, as a result of the sale, merger, consolidation, change in control, transfer of substantial assets, reorganisation or liquidation of Trading Name.

Abacus may make information concerning users of the Website available to law enforcement personnel and agencies when requested to do so or as required by law.

**Abacus**  
By providing any personal information to this Website, you fully understand and unambiguously consent to the transfer of such personal information to, and the collection and processing of such personal information in, the United Kingdom and other appropriate countries or territories. This Website may contain links or references to other websites outside of our control. Please be aware that we have no control over these sites and our privacy policy does not apply to these sites.

**Access**  
If you would like to review and/or update the information that you have provided to the Website, please send an email to website administration [abacus@abacusglobal.com](mailto:abacus@abacusglobal.com) requesting such access or change.

**Choice/Opt-out**  
You may choose to have your name taken off the Abacus e-mail list or have Abacus not provide your information to others in the future by (1) sending an email to website administration at Abacus [abacus@abacusglobal.com](mailto:abacus@abacusglobal.com) with the subject line "Unsubscribe to Abacus" or by (2) following instructions as provided in any e-mail message from Abacus.

**Your Acceptance of this Policy**  
By using this Website, you signify your acceptance of our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Website. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this policy at any time so visitors are encouraged to review this policy from time to time. Your continued use of our Website following the posting of changes to these terms means you accept these changes. 

Abacus Jersey, Abacus Financial Services Group, La Motte Chambers, St Helier, Jersey, JE1 1BJ, Channel Islands   
Tel    +44 (0)1534 602000  
Fax   +44 (0)1534 602002

Abacus Guernsey, Abacus Financial Services Group, National Westminster House, Le Truchot, St Peter Port, Guernsey, GY1 4PW, Channel Islands  
Tel    +44 (0)1481 732600  
Fax   +44 (0)1481 728493

Abacus London, Abacus Financial Services Group, Tower 42, 25 Old Broad Street, London, EC2N 1HN, United Kingdom  
Tel    +44 (0)207 877 2101  
Fax   +44 (0)207 877 2102

Abacus Edinburgh, Abacus Corporate Services International Limited, Exchange Tower, 8th Floor, PO Box 23535, 19 Canning Street, Edinburgh, EH3 8EG  
Tel    +44 (0)131 222 3600  
Fax   +44 (0)131 222 3601

Abacus Cheltenham, Abacus Financial Services Group, Fourth Floor, The Quadrangle, Imperial Square, Cheltenham, Gloucestershire, GL50 1PZ, United Kingdom  
Tel    +44 (0)124 254 8400  
Fax   +44 (0)124 254 8401

Abacus Amsterdam, Abacus Corporate Services International Limited, The Atrium (Third Floor), Strawinskylaan 3051, 1077 ZX Amsterdam, Netherlands  
Tel    +31 (0)20 301 2158  
Fax   +31 (0)20 301 2202
